Guide to the Peter Palmquist Cased Photographs Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Images by Identified Photographers, Series I; (161 items)
  - CALIFORNIA PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Selleck, Silas Wright (circa 1828-1885)
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856-60 (Box 4, Folder 31)
        Full brown papier-mache case with circular geometric floral motif.
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl and two boys, one boy wearing a dress, and the hand of a woman on the right edge of the image, circa 1856-60 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        Half-plate hand-tinted ruby-glass ambrotype; original seal
        Full brown leather case with grapevine cluster motif in center and floral scrolling
      - Tintype in a case, of a woman, circa 1856-60 (Box 4, Folder 33)
        Quarter-plate tintype; unsealed
        Full brown papier-mache case with floral bouquet motif in center and floral scrolling
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1856-60 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        Sixth-plate hand-tinted ambrotype; original seal
        Full black leather case with geometric scroll motif
      - Ambrotype in half of a case, of a woman, circa 1856-60 (Box 4, Folder 35)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with modern photographic paper case lining; no seal
        Half brown leather case
      - Tintype in a case, of a boy and a girl, circa 1857-60 (Box 4, Folder 36)
        Sixth-plate tintype; unsealed
        Full brown papier-mache case with "Birds and the Fountain" motif (Rinhart #93)
      - Ambrotype in a case, of two girls and two boys, circa 1858 (Box 4, Folder 37)
        Quarter-plate ruby-glass ambrotype with printing-out paper behind image; original seal
        Full leather case with variant of "Lily and Rose" motif (Rinhart #114)
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a boy, with a copy of Webster's Dictionary, circa 1858 (Box 4, Folder 38)
        Half-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing, backed with paper from published journal of the period; original seal
        Full brown leather case with rose bouquet motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man with a beard, circa 1858 (Box 4, Folder 39)
        Sixth-plate ruby-glass ambrotype; original seal
        Full black leather case with a "Thistle" motif (Rinhart #119)
    - Shaw & Johnson
      (Seth Louis Shaw and George Howard Johnson)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of two women and two men, circa 1852 (Box 4, Folder 40)
        Half-plate daguerreotype; modern seal
        Full leather case, "The Monument" motif (Rinhart #9); imprint in velvet mat, "SHAW & JOHNSON / ARTISTS / SAN FRANCISCO / CAL."
    - Shew, Jacob (1826-1879)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1855-56 (Box 5, Folder 41)
        Half-plate hand-tinted daguerreotype; modern seal
        Blindstamp on mat, lower right, "JACOB SHEW / SACRAMENTO"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man and woman, who holds a thermoplastic case, circa 1856 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        Full purple velvet case
    - Shew, William (1820-1903)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Items 126-131
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, circa 1851-56 (Box 5, Folder 43)
        Blindstamp lower right on mat, "WM. SHEW / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full leather case with floral motif and scrolling (similar case to Rinhart #114, imprinted in reverse)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man holding a large top hat, circa 1851-56 (Box 5, Folder 44)
        Blindstamp lower edge of the mat, "WM. SHEW / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full brown leather case with grapevines in a vase motif
        Pencil inscription on paper lining of case behind the image, "C.V.G. / 28.00"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, identified as William Waldo, circa 1851-56 (Box 5, Folder 45)
        Paper affixed to plate, "William Waldo"
        Sixth-plate daguerreotype; original seal
        Blindstamp lower corners of the mat, "WM. SHEW / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full leather case with the Interlaced Spiral motif (Rinhart #228)
        William Waldo (1832-1911), the son of Daniel and Malinda (Lunsford) Waldo, was a lawyer and served in the Oregon Legislature as a State Senator and President of the Senate
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1851-56 (Box 5, Folder 46)
        Quarter-plate daguerreotype; masking-tape seal
        Blindstamp lower left corner on mat, "WM. SHEW / 423 MONTGY. ST. / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full leather case with star-shaped medallion
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman holding daguerreotype case, circa 1851-56 (Box 5, Folder 47)
        Quarter-plate hand-tinted daguerreotype, modern case
        Full brown pigskin case with pressed flower motif
      - Daguerreotype with a horizontal orientation in a case, of two girls, a woman, and a man, circa 1851-56 (Box 5, Folder 48)
        Half-plate hand-tinted daguerreotype; partially sealed
        Full leather case with rose cameo motif
        Inscription on paper lining of case, "Wm. Shew"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a boy, circa 1854-60 (Box 5, Folder 49)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing; original seal
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "WM. SHEW / 423 MONTGY. ST. / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full brown papier-mache case with mixed flower bouquet motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl, circa 1854-56 (Box 5, Folder 50)
        Half-plate ambrotype
        Blindstamp on mat, lower left: "WM SHEW"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl, circa 1854-60 (Box 6, Folder 51)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing and oiled paper backing; original seal
        Full leather case with geometric motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of an infant and woman, circa 1854-60 (Box 6, Folder 52)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing, with a loose piece of brown cloth behind image; original seal
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "WM. SHEW"
        Full leather case with circular geometric floral motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1854-60 (Box 6, Folder 53)
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "WM. SHEW / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full brown leather case with floral motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1854-60 (Box 6, Folder 54)
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "WILLIAM SHEW / 113 MONTGY. ST. / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full leather case with floral wreath motif, imprinted by photographer George Howard Johnson; blindstamp in velvet, "Geo. H. Johnson / Artist / Sacramento"
        Case presumably mismatched by modern collector and originally contained a Johnson image
      - Ambrotype not in a case, of a man, circa 1854-60 (Box 6, Folder 55)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; original seal
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1854-60 (Box 6, Folder 56)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing
        Full brown thermoplastic case with the Washington Monument, Richmond, Virginia motif (Krainik #21); printed on paper lining behind image, "GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and burnished / Hinge. / S. PECK & CO., / MANUFACTURERS."
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, identified as Carrie Campbell Crittenden Pratt, circa 1855 (Box 6, Folder 57)
        Quarter-plate ruby glass ambrotype; sealed
        Blindstamp on mat lower left, "Wm. SHEW / 423 MONTG.Y ST. / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full brown leather case with flowers motif
        Two handwritten in ink inscriptions behind image: 1) "Carrie Campbell Crittenden / Pratt" and 2) "Carrie Campbell Crittenden / Pratt / (In yellow [indecipherable] dress worn / at her sisters wedding (Aunt Nancy) / Polly Perkins wore this dress / at Carolyn [unreadable name] wedding."
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a young man, circa 1856 (Box 6, Folder 58)
        Quarter-plate hand-tinted daguerreotype; unsealed
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "WM. SHEW", and lower right on mat, "SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full leather case with Vase with Fruits and Flowers motif (Rinhart #108)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1857 (Box 6, Folder 59)
        Sixth-plate daguerreotype; unsealed
        Full leather case with the Romanesque Urn motif (Rinhart #141)
      - Ambrotype with a horizontal orientation in half case of five women and four men, circa 1858-61 (Box 44, Folder 60)
        Whole-plate clear glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; partial seal and backed with printing-out paper
        Blindstamp on mat, lower left, "WM SHEW / 423 MONTG.Y. ST / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Label on case cover, "California / friends and / uncle Joseph"
      - Ambrotype with a horizontal orientation in a case, of a postmortem man, circa 1864 (Box 7, Folder 61)
        Half-plate clear glass ambrotype backed with blackened iron plate with blue ten-cent tax stamp affixed; stamp is torn and cancelled in with an ink inscription
        Blindstamp on mat, lower right corner, "Wm. SHEW / 423 MONTGOMERY ST. / SAN FRANCISCO"
    - Silver, O. B.
      Dutch Flat
      - Ambrotype in half case of an exterior view of a home in Dutch Flat, California, with a boy, two women, and two men posed standing in the yard and on the porch, 1854-65 (Box 7, Folder 62)
        Half-plate clear glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; mat is in front of image package; backed by modern blackened photographic paper
    - Spooner, John Pitcher (1845-1917)
      Stockton
      - Tintype in a case, of an infant, identified as probably the daughter of the photographer, 1873 Sep 5 (Box 7, Folder 63)
        Quarter-plate ferrotype; no seal
        Full brown thermoplastic case with Agrarian motif (Krainik #26); printed on paper lining, "GENUINE / UNION CASE, / IMPROVED. / Fine Gilt and Burnished/ Hinge./ Scovill Mfg. Co."
        Inscription on paper lining of case, "J. Pitcher Spooner / Photog. / Stockton / Cala. / 9/5/1873"
    - Vance, Robert H., 1825-1876
      - Empty quarter-plate case, circa 1853 (Box 7, Folder 64)
        Full brown papier-mache case imprint on velvet pad of case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Cover to half-plate case, circa 1853 (Box 7, Folder 65)
        Cover of brown plain pigskin case imprint on velvet pad of case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"; probably manufactured by H.A. Eichmeyer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
      - Ambrotype with a horizontal orientation in a case, of two girls, two boys, a woman, and a man, 1853-55 (Box 7, Folder 66)
        Blindstamp lower right on mat, "R. H. VANCE / SAN FRANCISCO"; blindstamp upper right on mat, "CUTTING'S PATENT/ JULY 4 & 11 1855"
        Full leather case with jeweled medallion with heart-shaped scrolls; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman and man, probably a wedding day portrait, circa 1855 (Box 7, Folder 67)
        Full leather case, geometric design; imprint on velvet pad of case: "R.H. VANCE'S/ PREMIUM DAGUERREAN & PATENT / AMBROTYPE GALLERY / SAN FRANCISCO & SACRAMENTO"
        May represent the earliest known photographic image of a full bridal costume in the American Pacific West
      - Ambrotype in a case, of seven men, identified as prominent San Francisco businessmen, circa 1855-56 (Box 45, Folder 68)
        Whole-plate clear glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing (tissue adhered); mat missing; partial seal
        Full brown leather case with geometric and scroll motif; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
        Possible identifications for individuals include, top row, from left to right, the first man, Cornelius Cole, John D. Fry, or Charles Bull Crocker; second man, William C. Ralston or Henry Huntley Haight; third man, Cornelius Kingsland Garrison or Thomas H. Selby; bottom row, left to right, first man, Ben Holladay or Joseph W. Winans; second man, William Walker or Ogden Hoffman; third man, William Tecomseh Sherman, Darius Ogden Mills, or William Sharon; fourth man, Henry Huntley Haight, Edward J. C. Kewen, or Sam Ralston
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl, circa 1856 (Box 46, Folder 69)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype; cracked plate upper right corner; original seal
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "R.H. VANCE", blindstamp lower right on mat: "CUTTING'S PAT. / JULY 4 & 11 1854"
        Companion image for Item 70, children from same family
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a boy, circa 1856 (Box 7, Folder 70)
        Companion image for Item 69, children from same family
      - Two ambrotypes in a case, one depicting a girl, the other depicting a woman, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 71)
        Both sixth-plate clear-glass hand-tinted ambrotypes backed with printing out paper; original seals; image of girl has crazed backing; image of woman has separation of balsam seal.
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "CUTTING'S PATENT / JULY 4 & 11 1854", blindstamp lower right on mat, "R.H. VANCE / SAN FRANCISCO"
        Full black double thermoplastic case with Bobby Shafto motif (Krainik #135 or Rinhart #25); printed on paper lining, "A.P. CRITCHLOW & CO., / Manufacturers of / Daguerreotype Cases. / A.P.C. & CO. / Are the Original Inventors of / the Composition for the Union Case, / (so called,) including all the various shades / of color and fineness of texture pecu- / liar to their manufacture and of the / EMBRACING RIVETED HINGES, thus / securing them from breaking out as/ do others that are inserted / with or without a / metal brace./ Hinge Patented / OCT. 14, 1856."
        The woman holds a leather ambrotype case
      - Ambrotype not in a case, of a girl, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 72)
        Half-plate clear-glass ambrotype; scotch-tape seal; separation of plate on right side
      - Ambrotype in a half case, of a girl, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 73)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; original seal; separation of balsam seal
        Blindstamp lower right on mat, "CUTTING'S PATENT / JULY 4 & 11 1854", blindstamp lower left on mat, "R.H. VANCE / SAN FRANCISCO"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a boy and a woman, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 74)
        Half-plate clear-glass hand-tinted ambrotype with asphaltum backing; original seal; separation of balsam seal
        Full double plain leather case; image can be viewed from both sides
        Same subjects as Item 75
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a boy and a woman, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 75)
        Half-plate clear-glass hand-tinted ambrotype with asphaltum backing; original seal
        Full leather case with an oriental motif
        Same subjects as Item 74
      - Ambrotype in a case, of two girls, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 76)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype in relievo
        Full leather case with floral bouquet motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of two girls, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 77)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype backed with black velvet; partially sealed
        Full red velvet case; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN & PATENT / AMBROTYPE GALLERY / SAN FRANCISCO"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl and a woman, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 78)
        Quarter-plate ambrotype; no seal
        Full brown papier-mache case; imprint on velvet pad of case: "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl and a woman, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 79)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype backed with black velvet; original seal
        Full leather case with elaborate circle motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman and a man, identified as Joseph Ramsdell and his wife, circa 1856 (Box 8, Folder 80)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype backed with tintype plate; original seal; separation of balsam seal
        Full plain leather case; blindstamp on lower back cover of case, "H.A. EICHMEYER, PATENT, FEB. 27 1855"; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
        Ink inscription on paper in the case, "Joseph Ramsdell / & wife. Mother, Celia Conniffa / Uncle, Aunt Corley's Brother"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of an infant and a woman, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 81)
        Sixth-plate clear glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; sealed
        Full brown leather case with geometric quatrefoil motif; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Ambrotype not in a case, of a woman and man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 82)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; image plate broken; no seal
        Attributed to Vance
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 83)
        Sixth-plate ambrotype
        Full brown papier-mache case
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 84)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing; original seal; separation of balsam seal
        Full plain leather case, blindstamp on lower back cover of case, "H.A. EICHMEYER, PATENT, FEB. 27 1855; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 85)
        Sixth-plate hand-tinted clear-glass ambrotype
        Full double plain pigskin case; image can be viewed from both sides
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 86)
        Quarter-plate ruby-glass ambrotype; original seal; separation of balsam seal
        Leather frame
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 87)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype, no seal
        Full brown leather case, imprint On velvet pad in case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN & PATENT / AMBROTYPE GALLERY / SAN FRANCISCO & SACRAMENTO"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 88)
        Full black thermoplastic case with Scroll motif (Krainik #326)
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 89)
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1856 (Box 9, Folder 90)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype; original seal
      - Ambrotype with a horizontal orientation in a case, of a girl, a woman, and a man, circa 1856 (Box 10, Folder 91)
        Half-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; original seal; dislocation of balsam seal
        Full leather case with geometric scroll motif; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of an elderly woman, circa 1856 (Box 10, Folder 92)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing; original seal
        Full papier-mache case with geometric medallion motif
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, identified as Elizabeth Margaret Livingston, circa 1856 (Box 10, Folder 93)
        Full leather case with goblet of flowers motif
        Labels affixed on back of case, "Elizabeth / [?] / Margaret / Livingston / Daughter / of / Stephen / Livingston"
    - Vance, Robert H., 1825-1876
      Sacramento or San Francisco
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a girl, a woman, and a man, 1856-63 (Box 10, Folder 94)
        Full plain leather case; imprint of velvet pad in case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN & PATENT / AMBROTYPE GALLERY / SAN FRANCISCO & SACRAMENTO"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a girl, a boy, and an elderly man, circa 1857 (Box 10, Folder 95)
        Full leather case; imprint of velvet pad in case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN & PATENT / AMBROTYPE GALLERY / SAN FRANCISCO & SACRAMENTO"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a boy, circa 1858 (Box 10, Folder 96)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish; original seal
        Full leather case with jeweled medallion and heart-shape scroll motif; imprint of velvet pad in case, "R.H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN & PATENT / AMBROTYPE GALLERY / SAN FRANCISCO & SACRAMENTO"
    - Vance, Robert H., 1825-1876
      Marysville, Sacramento, or San Francisco
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 10, Folder 97)
        Full leather case with geometric medallion motif; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 10, Folder 98)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype backed with asphaltum backing; no seal
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "CUTTING'S PATENT / JULY 4 & 11 1854"
        Full leather case with geometric oval medallion motif; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman and man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 10, Folder 99)
        Quarter-plate daguerreotype; original seal; some spotting on plate
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 10, Folder 100)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 101)
        Sixth-plate daguerreotype; sealed with masking tape
        Full leather case; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 102)
        Quarter-plate daguerreotype; sealed with scotch tape
      - Stereoscopic daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, probably dressed in mourning clothing, circa 1853-54 (Box 11, Folder 103)
        Two ninth-plate daguerreotypes to form a stereoscopic pair
        Quarter-plate thermoplastic case with Mascher viewer built in, imprinted "MASCHER'S IMPROVED STEREOSCOPE / PHILADA. / PATENT / MARCH 8TH 1853"; printed label in case, "FROM R. H. VANCE'S / DAGUERREAN ROOMS / SAN FRANCISCO, SACRAMENTO, & MARYSVILLE, / CAL."
        Imprint on case medallion, "OUR FATHER WHICH ART IN HEAVEN HALLOWED BE THY NAME / BUT DELIVER US FROM EVIL / MATTHEW V VI. 9"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of an African- American woman, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 104)
        Sixth-plate daguerreotype with metal backing plate; original seal
        Full brown leather case with the Rose Cameo motif (Rinhart #129); imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 105)
        Full leather case with geometric Center medallion motif; imprint on Velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 106)
        Full leather case with geometric floral scroll motif; imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a girl, a woman, and an elderly man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 107)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of two men, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 108)
        Quarter-plate daguerreotype; original seal.
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of four men, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 109)
        Full plain leather case imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 110)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; original seal